# **KENRICK TAM**

APPLYING FOR WEB DEVELOPER

**CONTACT** 

E: kenricktam@gmail.com
G: github.com/KnrkTam

P: 437 973 8229

# **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Programmer with industrial experiences building web application and CMS system. specialised in JavaScript & TypeScript and have professional experience working with PHP and Codelgniter. I also have experience working with ReactJs, NextJs, and Google Firebase.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## **Programming Language**

- Typescript
- Javascript
- Python
- PHP

### **Frontend**

- React is
- Next.is
- Material UI
- CSS, SCSS

## **Backend**

- PostgreSQL
- Express.js
- Node.js
- Knex (Migration)
- MySQL
- Codeigniter
- Google firebase

## **DevOps**

- AWS (EC2, S3, Route 53, Certificate Manager)
- Nginx

### **Others**

- Git
- Restful API

## **AVAILABILITY**

• Immediately Available

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## PROGRAMMER - ONE SOLUTION LIMITED

Dec 2020 to Jun 2022

- Built 3 web applications and CMS systems from scratch independently
- Constructed and designed the database structure
- · Maintained, updated and troubleshot for existing projects
- Attended business meeting to report and review project status
- · Skills: PHP, Codelgniter, MySQL

## ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - RECRUITFIRST LIMITED

Aug 2019 to Jul 2020

- Achieved monthly sales target for 7 consecutive months in 2020
- Liaised with clients and over 80 contract staff regularly on contract matters and iob enquiries
- Recruited, Negotiated and Delivered between our clients and candidates from TMT sector

# PERSONAL PROJECT EXPERIENCE

## NEXT-FIRE - DEMO PROJECT OF REACT, NEXT.JS & FIREBASE

Demo project | Jul 2022

- Demo project with ReactJS, Next.js & Google Firebase
- Deployed with Vercel and database on Firestore

## **ZPACE - SMALL WORKSPACE SHARING PLATFORM**

Group capstone project at Tecky Academy | Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

- SPA website developed with React.js (frontend) & Express.js (backend)
- The end-product supports user-login (OAuth), search by geolocation (GoogleMAP API), real-time chat-box (Socket.io), rating and bookmark features

## MAHJONGCENA - A.I. MAHJONG SCANNER & SCOREBOARD

A.I. project | Oct 2020

- A Mahjong winning hands calculation tool with A.I. tile recognition features (cv2, TensorFlow, YOLO models: Darknet & MobileNet)
- Tailored web interface for Mahjong users with designed features including scoreboard, animated dice-rolling and game-point records

# **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### **TECKY ACADEMY**

MicroMaster in A.I. and Programming (cohort 11), Aug to Dec 2020

- 15 weeks Full-Time immersive course with several real-world projects
- Including SPA website and A.I. employed web-based application

#### THE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

Class of 2018. Graduated with Upper second class honours

· Majored in Psychology